uso.org 2018-12-28

# Privacy Policy · United Service Organizations

The United Service Organizations, Inc. ( **“USO”** ) is committed to protecting the privacy of visitors and registered users (collectively, “users”) of our websites. We want to ensure that our users understand the types of information that the USO collects, the ways in which the USO uses and protects that information, and the choices that they have about the collection and use of their information. Accordingly, we have created this Privacy Policy to communicate our practices regarding the collection and dissemination of: (1) personally identifiable information that can be linked to a specific individual (such as a name or mailing address), and (2) any other information provided to us by users of our websites. 

In this Privacy Policy, the terms “we,” “us,” and “our” refer to the USO. The terms “you,” and “your” refer to both visitors and registered users of the USO Websites (as defined below). 

To assist you in reviewing our Privacy Policy, we have divided it into the following topics:

  * Application of the Privacy Policy
  * Changes to the Privacy Policy
  * Acceptance of the Privacy Policy
  * Types of Information that the USO Collects and Uses
  * Use of Personal Information by the USO
  * Sharing of Personal Information by the USO
  * Use of Personal Information Collected Offline by the USO
  * Opt-Out Policy
  * Use of Financial Information by the USO
  * Use of Email Address by the USO
  * How to Update or Change Your Personal Information
  * California Privacy Rights
  * Collection of Information from Children
  * Tell-A-Friend and Email This Page Services
  * Submitting Messages and Stories to the USO
  * Use of “Cookies”
  * How the USO Secures Personal Information You Submit Online
  * How the USO Secures Personal Information You Provide by Telephone, Regular Mail, or In Person
  * External Links
  * Privacy Policy Claims
  * For More Information

### _Application of the Privacy Policy:_

This Privacy Policy applies to the following websites: [http://www.uso.org](http://www.uso.org/) (and each sub-domain associated with this URL), and other websites operated by or for the USO (collectively, the **“USO Websites”** ), including, but not limited to, USOmoments.org. The USO’s Chartered Centers are organized as independent nonprofit corporations and have their own privacy policies, which you should consult when visiting their respective websites. This Privacy Policy does not apply to other websites that may be accessible through the USO Websites, or to the practices of individuals or entities that the USO does not control, manage, and/or employ. The USO Websites may contain links to other websites that are operated by third parties, including, but not limited to, third-party websites that may display the name, trademarks, service marks, and logos of the USO. Before using any services or programs offered by these third-party websites, it is important for you to review their separate privacy policies to learn how they collect and use information about you. In order to fully understand your rights, we encourage you to read this Privacy Policy, as well as our [Terms Of Use](https://www.uso.org/terms-of-use).

### _Changes to the Privacy Policy:_

The USO is continually adopting new technologies to improve the services and programs offered by the USO Websites. Consequently, this Privacy Policy is subject to change and the USO reserves the right to update it at any time and without notice. Changes to the Privacy Policy will be posted here, so we encourage you to review the Privacy Policy from time-to-time. All changes to the Privacy Policy will be effective immediately upon posting.

### _Acceptance of the Privacy Policy:_

By using the USO Websites, you expressly consent to the use and disclosure of information as outlined in this Privacy Policy. By submitting any of your personally identifying information to us, you are agreeing that the USO may use such Personal Information (as defined below) in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Your continued use of the USO Websites after the effective date of any changes to the Privacy Policy shall be deemed to be your consent to the modified terms.

### _Types of Information that the USO Collects and Uses:_

When you visit the USO Websites, we may collect two types of information about you: 

  1. Personal Information
  2. Aggregate Information.

__Personal Information:__  
“Personal Information” is information that you provide to the USO that personally identifies you, such as your name, mailing address, zip code, telephone number, email address, billing information, or other data that can be reasonably linked to a specific individual by the USO. Personal Information is only collected online when you voluntarily submit non-public, personally identifiable information to the USO Websites, such as when you request information from the USO, donate to or purchase products from the USO, register to volunteer at a USO Center, or other similar communications and activities. Personal Information does not include any information that is posted or sent by or to you in any public forum (such as a message board, blog, or social networking service like Facebook or Twitter). Participation in these public forums requires the public release and dissemination of personally identifiable information, and therefore, the USO cannot commit to treating such information confidentially in the same manner that it treats other Personal Information under this Privacy Policy. Participation in these public forums is voluntary, your consent to certain terms is often required before use is allowed, and you control what personally identifiable Information may be disclosed to others. In order to avoid your personally identifiable information from being gathered and used by third parties for unsolicited, inappropriate, or harmful purposes, the USO advises that you exercise caution about posting such sensitive information to blogs, message boards, or other public forums.

__Aggregate Information:__  
“Aggregate Information” is non-personally identifiable information that is recorded about you so that it no longer reflects or references an individually identifiable user. Aggregate Information is used in a collective manner, and this compiled data does not allow us to personally identify any specific user. When you visit the USO Websites, we automatically collect Aggregate Information about your visit. Gathering this data helps us evaluate how the USO Websites are being used. Aggregate Information allows us to adjust the content of the USO Websites to make it more relevant to our users. The collection of Aggregate Information may be done by the use of cookies by the USO and its third-party service providers. In particular, the USO collects an IP Address from each user of the USO Websites, which is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. Except with respect to your e-commerce activities on the USO Websites (for example, making an online donation or purchasing products from the USO), IP Addresses are not linked to Personal Information. We may share Aggregate Information with our sponsors, service providers, the media, or other third parties in order to disseminate information, and otherwise advance the goals of our Mission.

### _Use of Personal Information by the USO:_

We do not use the USO Websites to collect any Personal Information about you, other than what you elect to provide voluntarily. You do not need to give us any Personal Information about yourself in order to access most of the USO Websites. You can visit the USO Websites, read our publications, and learn about our Mission and activities on an anonymous basis. In order to utilize certain features of the USO Websites or receive information from the USO, you may choose to provide Personal Information. If you do submit Personal Information to us, we will use that Personal Information for the purposes for which it was submitted. Generally, our uses of Personal Information collected online include responding to user inquiries about volunteering time to the USO, assisting users in making a donation to the USO or in purchasing a product from the USO, or providing information to users, such as newsletters, magazines, and other publications or marketing communications. We may use such voluntarily provided Personal Information to improve our understanding of your interests, to expand our services, or to contact you for future support, either by email, postal mail, telephone, or short message service **(“SMS”)**. We may collect demographic information from other sources to help us learn more about user characteristics and needs. We may also use your Personal Information in other ways, such as to contact you about other USO activities and/or fundraising campaigns, or as otherwise disclosed to you at the point of collection. We may also use your name, postal delivery information, and telephone number to contact you offline. If you do not wish for the USO to use your Personal Information to contact you offline, or if you do not wish to receive marketing communications from the USO, you can opt out at any time. Please send a request by email to: [info@uso.org](mailto:info@uso.org), or by postal mail to: **USO, Attention: Donor Services, P.O. Box 96860, Washington, DC 20090-6322**. Please  include your full name, mailing address, and telephone number in your opt-out request. You should stop receiving these communications about twelve (12) weeks from the date of your opt-out request.

### _Sharing of Personal Information by the USO:_

The USO takes seriously its commitment to safeguard your Personal Information. We do not sell or rent any Personal Information to telemarketers or mailing list brokers. The USO may need to share Personal Information with third parties in limited circumstances. For example, the USO uses third-party vendors to provide certain administrative services on the USO Websites and in offline business operations. The Personal Information that you submit on the USO Websites may be provided to those approved vendors on a confidential basis so that those vendors can provide services (such as maintaining our database, sending email updates, facilitating fundraising activities, or processing credit card transactions) on our behalf. We will require any approved vendor to whom we release your Personal Information to hold such information in strict confidence. While we believe these companies will treat your Personal information responsibly, we do not own or control them and cannot guarantee your privacy. Periodically, we may share Personal Information, such as your name and mailing address, with specifically selected nonprofit organizations in “list exchanges” conducted by the USO and these organizations for the purpose of enlisting potential new donors. This means that you may receive communications from other nonprofit groups that have agreed to participate in list exchanges with the USO, subject to approval of the USO.

From time-to-time, we may also share your name and mailing address with certain direct marketing companies so that they may contact you about products, services, or offers that we think would be of interest to you. 

Occasionally, we may be required to release Personal Information or Aggregate Information in response to a valid court order, subpoena, government investigation, or as otherwise required by law, or to enforce the [Terms of Use](https://www.uso.org/terms-of-use) applicable to the USO Websites, or if we reasonably believe that you have committed unlawful acts or acts that may endanger the health or safety of another user or the general public. We also reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we, in good faith, believe to be unlawful. We may release certain Personal Information when we believe that such release is reasonably necessary to protect the rights, property, and safety of others and/or our organization.

We also reserve the right to share, assign, or transfer your Personal Information to any of our affiliates or any successor in interest to our organization by merger, reorganization, or operation of law.

Other than as described in this Privacy Policy, or as may be necessary to protect the rights, property and safety of our organization or others, or as may  be necessary to comply with applicable law, the USO will not give or sell the Personal Information that you provide online.

### _Use of Personal Information Collected Offline by the USO:_

The USO treats the Personal Information that you submit to the USO offline (e.g., via telephone, regular mail, or in person) in the same manner that the USO treats Personal Information submitted online via the USO Websites, as outlined above.

### _Opt-Out Policy:_

If you do not wish for the USO to share, sell, or exchange your Personal Information with any third party for fundraising or marketing purposes, you may opt out at any time. Please send a request by email to: [info@uso.org](mailto:info@uso.org), or by postal mail to:  **USO, Attention: Donor Services, P.O. Box 96860, Washington, DC 20090-6322**. Please include your full name and mailing address in your opt-out request.

### _Use of Financial Information by the USO:_

If you choose to make an online donation or purchase merchandise from the USO, you will have to provide your credit or debit card billing information, including your card number and expiration date. This information is collected and transferred over the Internet using Secure Socket Layer ( **SSL** ) encryption technology to our secure server. If you are making a donation or purchase from the USO, the credit or debit card information that you provide at the time of donation or purchase is used only to process your donation or purchase, and will not be used or stored by USO for any other purposes. To process recurring sustainer donations, credit or debit card information or other digital payment processing information will be used and stored.

### _Use of Email Address by the USO:_

The USO does not collect your email address online unless you voluntarily submit it via a form on the USO Websites. When you donate to the USO, you will be asked to supply your email address. Your email address is only available to the USO employees who manage this information for purposes of contacting you or responding to user requests, and to contracted vendors for purposes of providing services relating to our communications with you. 

We may use your email address to send you information about the USO (such as news and events, special programs, and fundraising campaigns). From time-to-time, we may also send out email messages that might include information about like-minded organizations and companies, but we do not provide these entities with access to any Personal Information that you have submitted to us. 

The USO complies with the Controlling the Assault of Non-Solicited Pornography and Marketing (CAN-SPAM) Act of 2003. All marketing email messages from the USO tell you how to stop receiving them, and contain a link to unsubscribe from USO email. You may subscribe or unsubscribe to USO email at any time.  
[Click here](http://action.uso.org/unsubscribe) to unsubscribe from USO email online, or send postal mail to: **USO, Attention: Donor Services/Unsubscribe, P.O. Box 96860, Washington, DC 20090-6322**.

### _How to Update or Change Your Personal Information:_

The USO wants your Personal Information to be accurate and complete. To update or change your Personal Information, send your updated Personal Information by email to: [info@uso.org](mailto:info@uso.org), or by postal mail to: **USO, Attention: Donor Services, P.O. Box 96860, Washington, DC 20090-6322**.

### _California Privacy Rights:_

If you are a resident of California, you are entitled to request the following information, which we will provide to you free of charge: (1) a list of the types of Personal Information that we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year; and (2) the names and addresses of all third parties that received Personal Information in these categories from us in the preceding calendar year, and examples of the products and/or services marketed by these businesses. Please direct your request for these types of information by email to: [info@uso.org](mailto:info@uso.org), or by postal mail to: **USO, Attention: Donor Services, P.O. Box 96860, Washington, DC 20090-6322**.

### _Collection of Information from Children:_

The USO Websites are not designed specifically for children, and the USO does not intentionally collect Personal Information from or knowingly market to children under the age of 13. If we discover that we have inadvertently collected Personal Information from a person under the age of 13, we will delete such information as quickly as reasonably practicable. In the event that you become aware of a child under the age of 13 posting Personal Information to USO Websites without verifiable consent from a parent or guardian, please contact USO by email to: [info@uso.org](mailto:info@uso.org), or by postal mail to: **USO, Attention: Donor Services, P.O. Box 96860, Washington, DC 20090-6322**.

### _Tell-A-Friend and Email This Page Services:_

If you elect to use one of our sharing services to inform a friend about an article, image, or other feature of the USO Websites, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. The USO will automatically send the friend a one-time email communication welcoming them to the USO. Please know that the USO will only store this information to send an introductory email and for analytical purposes. The email address will not be added to any USO email list. Your friend may request the removal of his or her name and email address from the USO database at any time by email to: [info@uso.org](mailto:info@uso.org), or by postal mail to: **USO, Attention: Donor Services, P.O. Box 96860, Washington, DC 20090-6322**.

### _Submitting Messages and Stories to the USO:_

For information about our policies regarding the use of messages of support, stories, photographs, and other submissions that you make to the USO, please refer to our [Terms of Use](https://www.uso.org/terms-of-use).

### _Use of “Cookies”:_

The USO Websites may use “cookies” and similar means to collect Aggregate Information to enhance your experience while using the USO Websites. As discussed above, Aggregate Information does not identify any individual person. We may use or disclose Aggregate Information for any purpose. 

A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your computer’s hard drive by a webpage server. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and are designed to be read only by a webpage server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. Cookies are also used to make web-surfing easier by performing certain functions, such as recognizing personal preferences, saving your passwords, and temporarily storing session information and past activity in order to provide better service and easier access when you return to the USO Websites. 

Cookies do not allow us to identify you by name, email address, or other personally identifiable information. We use cookies primarily to identify returning users, understand user demographics, and make your experience on the USO Websites more relevant and convenient. 

We use third-party advertisers to create and distribute information about the USO on our behalf, including, but not limited to, remarketing with Google Analytics, Google Display Network Impression reporting, Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting and other integrated services that allow Google Analytics to collect data via advertising cookies and anonymous unique identifiers. These advertisers may also employ cookies and action tags (also known as single pixel gifs or web beacons) to measure advertising effectiveness. An action tag is an image file contained in an advertisement or other content that indicates when the ad or the content has loaded onto a user’s screen. Any information these third parties collect via cookies and action tags is anonymous, unless there is a premium award associated with the donation or the USO is otherwise required to confirm donation activity to the referring third party. 

If you would prefer not to allow cookies to be placed on your computer, you should change the settings on your Internet browser so that it will not accept cookies, or so that it will notify you whenever a website is trying to use cookies. If you choose not to allow cookies, however, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the USO Websites or other websites that you visit, and it is possible that some aspects of the USO Websites may not function properly when you access them. If you disable cookies, you will still be able to visit most USO Websites on an anonymous basis, just as you have in the past.

### _How the USO Secures Personal Information You Submit Online:_

The USO Websites have security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. The USO uses commercially reasonable safeguards to ensure the security and privacy of the Personal Information that you provide to us, and tailors these protections to the sensitivity of the type of Personal Information gathered. The USO uses commercially reasonable efforts to ensure that any third parties to whom it may transfer any Personal Information have knowledge of this Privacy Policy and provide sufficient protection of such Personal Information. The USO requires that a secure session be established using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) when you submit Personal Information to us through your use of the USO Websites to enter credit or debit card information for payment or a donation, and visit particular pages on the USO Websites. The USO uses Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard ( **PCI DSS** ) compliant practices when handling user credit or debit card information on the USO Websites. The USO only uses accredited digital certificate signers on the USO Websites. The USO takes the following steps to secure the Personal Information that we collect online:

  * We use technical access control procedures, including, but not limited to: industry standard Secure Socket Layer ( **SSL** ) technology, encryption, network firewalls, and password protections.
  * We adhere to PCI DSS compliant practices.
  * We only provide Personal Information to authorized employees and agents who require it to perform their professional assignments.
  * We regularly back up the information that we collect online to insure against loss.
  * We routinely assess our security procedures to assure personnel and technical compliance. Personal Information stored on the USO Websites will be collected, stored, and processed in the United States of America.

While we follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the Personal Information submitted to us, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100 percent secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

### _How the USO Secures Personal Information You Provide by Telephone, Regular Mail, or In Person_

The USO utilizes the same policies and procedures outlined above to protect the privacy of any Personal Information voluntarily submitted by you to the USO via telephone, regular mail, or in person. If you have any questions about any Personal Information you have provided via one of these off-line methods, you may contact us by email to: [info@uso.org](mailto:info@uso.org) or by telephone at: 800-854-0535.

### _External Links:_

Links to other websites that are included on the USO Websites do not imply an endorsement of the materials disseminated at those websites, nor does the existence of a link to another website imply that the organization or person publishing at that website endorses any of the materials at the USO Websites. Links to other websites are provided by the USO as a convenience to its users. The USO is not responsible for materials contained at any website linked to the USO Websites. If you visit the websites of any of our partners, please consult their respective privacy policies. Our Privacy Policy applies only to your use of the USO Websites. We do not disclose personally identifiable information to those operating linked websites and we are not responsible for their privacy practices.

### _Privacy Policy Claims:_

The USO has designated a Privacy Manager who is responsible for ensuring USO’s online compliance with this Privacy Policy. If you have a claim regarding our compliance with this Privacy Policy, you can contact our Privacy Manager by email at: [info@uso.org](mailto:info@uso.org), or by postal mail to: **USO, Attention: Donor Services, P.O. Box 96860, Washington, DC20090-6322**. Please provide a detailed description of your claim to allow our Privacy Manager to fully investigate any issue that you have and respond promptly to you.

### _For More Information:_

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the privacy practices of the USO Websites, please contact the USO by:  
Email: [info@uso.org](mailto:info@uso.org)

Telephone: 800-854-0535  
Postal Mail:  
USO  
Attention: Donor Services  
P.O. Box 96860  
Washington, DC 20090-6322 

For more information about online privacy issues generally, we encourage you to visit the Federal Trade Commission website at  
[http://www.ftc.gov](http://www.ftc.gov/) or  
<http://www.usa.gov/topics/family/privacy-protection/online.shtml>.

_LAST UPDATED: May 4, 2016_
